# **Alex Clapperton**

10 Brierley Avenue, Whitefield, Manchester, M45 7RD 0161 767 9878 / 07930 946 211 | hi@alexclapperton.co.uk alexclapperton.co.uk

## **Professional Profile**

A final year Web Development student with excellent web development and communication skills developed through personal development and working in the digital industry for the last 2 years. Through my role as a Web Developer over the last two years, I understand the importance of good semantic HTML and CSS as well as the importance of accessibility. I also understand the benefits of tools such as Git, Sass and Gulp, to help improve workflow amongst and individual and a team, as well as techniques such as the BEM methodology to help make CSS code scalable and maintainable.

### Education

Manchester Metropolitan University

2013 - 2017

2008 - 2010

BSc(Hons) Web Development

Expected Grade: 2:1

Bury College

A Levels: Media Studies (C) and Film Studies (C)

Philips High School 2003 – 2008

GCSEs: 8 A-C grades including English (C) and Maths (C)

# Relevant Work Experience

Nuttersons 2015 - Present

#### Web Developer (Part-time)

Role includes building responsive websites for any new clients to a professional standard as well as maintaining current client websites such as improving design of a website to a modern standard and making any old websites responsive.

- **Mobile First:** Implementing mobile first design in all websites I build, building all websites for mobile screen sizes, then building up to desktop screen sizes.
- Workflow: Over the last year I have started to use a variety of tools to help improve workflow for myself as well as the rest of my team. These tools include the likes of **Git** to improve how we manage our web projects, **Gulp** to minify my HTML, CSS and to perform other tasks and using **Sass** to make styling websites more efficient.

The Hut Group
UX Developer (Internship)

June 2016 - September 2016

Role includes reducing technical debt and improve Sass code across the code base to improve code to be more scalable and maintainable across the team.

- Technical Debt: Trying to update old Sass code and make it scalable and understandable across the team. Using the BEM methodology to make improve the Sass code.
- Sass Components: Taking similar areas across all websites owned by The Hut Group and breaking them down into Sass components and adding to the company's toolkit to make it easier to maintain the code and to improve new website builds.

## Additional Work Experience

**Granada Batteries Ltd** 2009 - 2015

## Warehouse Operative (Part-time & Full-time)

Role includes working both as part of a small team and lone working, taking care of various duties within the warehouse such as stock management, monitoring deliveries, customer service and packing.

- Time Management: I had to effectively prepare and pack orders that came through so that they are ready to be dispatched by the end of day.
- Accuracy: With orders coming through at a pace, I had to make sure I picked all items ordered by the customers correctly.

# **Key Skills**

#### Technical skills:

- Always use Gulp as my task manager
- Always use Git to manage projects
- Excellent understanding of HTML and CSS
- Recently used Metalsmith as my static site generator
- Recently used Handlebars for my templating

#### Soft skills:

- Excellent communication skills
- Can work effectively as an individual as well Always willing to share ideas with others as in a team
- Always willing to learn nee tools techniques

#### **Interests**

- I enjoy playing five-a-side football with my friends and regularly play two times a week at the Powerleague Soccer Dome in Manchester. I can play in net as well as and outfield player.
- I am fully committed to learning new things to make me a better developer so I often find myself heading to websites like CSS-Tricks to see what the latest trend is.

### References

Available on request.